<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: conference | Matthias Feys]]></title>
  <link href="http://Fematich.github.io/blog/categories/conference/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Fematich.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-19T11:28:54+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://Fematich.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matthias Feys]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ECIR2014]]></title>
    <link href="http://Fematich.github.io/blog/2014/04/16/ecir2014/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-16T15:52:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://Fematich.github.io/blog/2014/04/16/ecir2014</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ecir2014.org/">ECIR2014</a> was hosted in Amsterdam and was the first conference I ever visited. It was a very enriching experience.
Some interesting papers related to my research (with their abstracts) are listed below:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Boilerplate Detection and Recoding</strong>: Many information access applications have to tackle natural
language texts that contain a large proportion of repeated and mostly
invariable patterns – called boilerplates –, such as automatic templates,
headers, signatures and table formats. These domain-specific standard
formulations are usually much longer than traditional collocations or
standard noun phrases and typically cover one or more sentences. Such
motifs clearly have a non-compositional meaning and an ideal document
representation should reflect this phenomenon.
We propose here a method that detects automatically and in an un-
supervised way such motifs; and enriches the document representation
by including specific features for these motifs. We experimentally show
that this document recoding strategy leads to improved classification on
different collections.</li>
<li><strong>GTE-Cluster: A Temporal Search Interface for Implicit Temporal Queries(demo)</strong>:In this paper, we present GTE-Cluster an online temporal search
interface which consistently allows searching for topics in a temporal
perspective by clustering relevant temporal Web search results. GTE-Cluster is
designed to improve user experience by augmenting document relevance with
temporal relevance. The rationale is that offering the user a comprehensive
temporal perspective of a topic is intuitively more informative than retrieving a
result that only contains topical information. Our system does not pose any
constraint in terms of language or domain, thus users can issue queries in any
language ranging from business, cultural, political to musical perspective, to
cite just a few. The ability to exploit this information in a temporal manner can
be, from a user perspective, potentially useful for several tasks, including user
query understanding or temporal clustering.</li>
<li><p><strong>Metric Spaces for Temporal Information Retrieval</strong>: Documents and queries are rich in temporal features, both
at the meta-level and at the content-level. We exploit this information
to define temporal scope similarities between documents and queries in
metric spaces. Our experiments show that the proposed metrics can
be very effective for modeling the relevance for different search tasks,
and provide insights into an inherent asymmetry in temporal query
semantics. Moreover, we propose a simple ranking model that combines the temporal scope similarity with traditional keyword similarities.
We experimentally show that it is not worse than traditional keyword-based rankings for non-temporal queries, and that it improves the overall
effectiveness for time-based queries.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Time-Aware Focused Web Crawling</strong>:There is a plethora of information inside the Web. Even the
top commercial search engines can not download and index all the available information. So, in the recent years, there are several research works
on the design and implementation of focused topic crawlers and also on
geographic scope crawlers.
Despite other areas of information retrieval, research on Web crawling is not using the temporal information extracted from Web pages in
the used crawling criteria. Therefore, our research challenge is the use of
temporal data extracted from Web pages as the main crawling criteria
to satisfy a given temporal focus. The importance of the time dimension is quite amplified when combined with topic or geography, but now
we want to study it isolated. The used approach is based on temporal
segmentation of Web pages text. It only follows links within segments
tagged with dates in the scope of restriction. A precision around 75%
was achieved in preliminary experimental results.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Automatically Retrieving Explanatory Analogies from Webpages</strong>:Explanatory analogies make learning complex concepts easier by
elaborately mapping a target concept onto a more familiar source concept. Solu-
tions exist for automatically retrieving shorter metaphors from natural language
text, but not for explanatory analogies. In this paper, we propose an approach to
find webpages containing explanatory analogies for a given target concept. For
this, we propose the use of a ‘region of interest’ (ROI) based on the observation
that linguistic markers and source concept often co-occur with various forms of
the word ‘analogy’. We also suggest an approach to identify the source con-
cept(s) contained in a retrieved analogy webpage. We demonstrate these ap-
proaches on a dataset created using Google custom search to find candidate web
pages that may contain analogies.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Temporal Expertise Proﬁling</strong>:We introduce the temporal expertise profiling task: identifying the
skills and knowledge of an individual and tracking how they change over time. To
be able to capture and distinguish meaningful changes, we propose the concept of
a hierarchical expertise profile, where topical areas are organized in a taxonomy.
Snapshots of hierarchical profiles are then taken at regular time intervals. Further, we develop methods for detecting and characterizing changes in a person’s
profile, such as, switching the main field of research or narrowing/broadening the
topics of research. Initial results demonstrate the potential of our approach.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Towards an Entity–Based Automatic Event Validation</strong>:Event Detection algorithms infer the occurrence of real–world
events from natural language text and always require a ground truth
for their validation. However, the lack of an annotated and comprehensive ground truth makes the evaluation onerous for humans, who
have to manually search for events inside it. In this paper, we envision
to automatize the evaluation process by defining the novel problem of
Entity–based Automatic Event Validation. We propose a first approach
which validates events by estimating the temporal relationships among
their representative entities within documents in the Web. Our approach
reached a Kappa Statistic of 0.68 when compared with the evaluation of
real–world events done by humans. This and other preliminary results
motivate further research effort on this novel problem.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
